NIKITA KOSTIN

Espoo, Finland · nskostin96@gmail.com · +358414960156 · Personal webpage · LinkedIn

PROFILE

Highly initiative and self-motivated machine learning engineer with 6+ years of academic and industry experience. Proficient in Python and has solid knowledge of machine learning algorithms. Proven record of contributions to software development projects from top tech companies. Demonstrated teamwork and supervision skills in several academic and industrial projects. Have legal rights to work in EU.

SKILLS

Python, C++, PyTorch, HuggingFace, Pandas, ROS2, Git, Docker, LaTex. Software tools: English (C1), Swedish (B1), German (A2), Finnish (A1), Russian (native). Languages:

Work experience

Aalto University Espoo, Finland Research Scientist Nov 2021 - Present

- Research in safe and robust reinforcement learning algorithms for robotics.
- Developed uncertainty-aware safe exploration for reinforcement learning using a Bayesian cost model, making the agent safely operate in complex, unknown environments (under review).
- Developed robust reinforcement learning algorithm for fast adaptation to unseen dynamical changes using adaptive control (under review).
- Developing natural language-constrained safe reinforcement learning using LLM and VLM experience labeling.

Huawei Research Center

Moscow, Russia Sep 2019 - Oct 2021

Machine Learning Engineer

- Research and development of deep learning algorithms for image enhancement and super-resolution.
- Developed an algorithm for demosaicing of underscreen camera photos that improved the quality by 25%.
- Developed a super-resolution algorithm based on Normalizing Flows that improved the quality of the underscreen camera photos by 13%.

Samsung R&D Institute

Moscow, Russia Jun 2018 - Aug 2019

Machine Learning Engineer

- Research and development of automation algorithms for cloud and mobile applications.
- Developed OpenStack system installation automation, accelerated system's deployment to new locations.
- Developed AI-based Mobile Testing Automation for Android using Reinforcement Learning, which accelerated new features testing by 50%.

EDUCATION

Boomion	
Aalto University PhD in Electrical Engineering, GPA: 4.52, Courses: Deep Learning, Bayesian Statistics	Espoo, Finland Jan 2022 - Present
Lomonosov Moscow State University M.Sc in Applied Mathematics, GPA: 4.05, Courses: Control Engineering, Optimal Control	Moscow, Russia Sep 2018 - May 2020
Lomonosov Moscow State University B.Sc in Physics, <i>GPA</i> : 4.51, Courses: Calculus, Linear Algebra, Physics, C++	Moscow, Russia Sep 2014 - May 2018
Contification	

Certificates

• Generative AI with Large Language Models, Coursera, Jul 2024.

Conferences and Workshops

Teaching assistant at ProbAI

Lead TA on Normalizing Flows section of Nordic Probabilistic AI summer school.	Jun 2022
Teaching assistant on RL course	Helsinki, Finland
TA and lecturer on the Reinforcement Learning course.	Sep 2022 - Present
International Workshop of Intelligent Autonomous Learning Systems	Kleinwalsertal, Austria
Organized by the Intelligent Autonomous Systems lab from TU Darmstadt.	Aug 2023

Generative Modeling Summit

Belgrade, Serbia

Helsinki, Finland

Organized by Yandex, it presented the latest technologies behind YaGPT.

ELLIS Robust Machine Learning Workshop

Helsinki, Finland

Workshop covered important topics of robustness of ML, LLMs and Human-Computer Interaction.

Jun 2024

Sep 2023